Oleksandr Kochenko

Full Stack Developer

I am a highly motivated Full Stack developer with proficiency in the most modern frontend and backend tools and technologies. I have practical skills in working with Agile/Scrum methodology. I learn fast with passion and persistence. My previous work background gives me strong self-organization and task-responsibility skills, as well as good experience in managing projects, meeting deadlines and solving problem situations.

Core competencies and skills

- Full-cycle application development
- Web applications maintaining and optimizing
- Servers and databases setup and maintenance
- REST API development and integration
- Authentication and authorization modules
- Security and data protection settings
- Project deployment, distribution and presentation
- Technical documentation and reports

Tools and technologies

- JavaScript / TypeScript
- React / Redux
- Next.js
- Material UI / Chakra UI
- Tailwind CSS
- Node.js / Express
 - NestJs
 - PostgreSQL / GraphQL
- MongoDB / Mongoose
 - REST API

- Docker / AWS / Vercel
- Swagger / Postman
- GIT
- Figma
- SCRUM

Work experience

Full Stack Developer | Freelance

May 2024 - Current

- Full-cycle developing of applications, web-sites and landing pages
- Servers and databases setup, maintenance and operations
- Projects deployment, SEO optimization, consultation on online business representation

Junior Full Stack Developer | Trioweb SA | Sparelys ™ (web-shop)

December 2022 - May 2024

- developing an authentication system for the management system of web-shop
- · developing of an admin panel to manage customers and users data of web-shop in order to overview special offers, manage customer's data, create and send links to customers, get statistics, create and update new users (online managers), etc.
- · developing a customer's landing page, that allows the customer to review his special offers, inspect products details, print or download the offer, contact to the web-shop manager and finally decline or submit
- · updating and improving UI/UX of web-shop pages (navigation, search, autocomplete, notifications, color scheme, visual effects, readability, responsive design etc.)
- testing the web-shop and the management system of web-shop after system version updating and database updating

Front End Developer | Freelance

April 2022 - December 2022

- creating, maintaining and optimizing web pages and corporate web sites
- cross-browser testing, debugging and improvement of web applications
- web page UI/UX and SEO optimization
- creating tools that improve site interaction regardless of the browser
- fixing bugs and testing web sites for usability

Frontend Developer Intern | Smart LLC (Ads and IT services agency)

December 2021 - February 2022

- creating web pages and corporate web site
- implementing responsive design
- · optimizing web site performance
- · redesigning user interface

Education

Full stack development course | GoIT: IT School

November 2022 - July 2023

Front end development for switchers course | EPAM Academy

September 2022 - December 2022

IT fundamentals for Ukrainian switchers course | EPAM Academy

May 2022 - August 2022

Online marketing course | Level 80: Online-marketing School

September 2020 - December 2020

Master's degree in Marketing | Kyiv National Economic University

September 1995 - June 2000

Soft skills

- Task responsibility
- Easy learning
- Communication skills
- Teamwork skills
- Fast adaptation
- Attention to detail
- Organizational and time management skills

Languages

English: Upper IntermediatePolish: Upper Intermediate

• Norwegian : Pre Intermediate

Ukrainian : NativeRussian : Native

Projects

<u>Ukrainian-Canadian Association "Tryzub" Web Page</u> [React, Tailwind, Express, MongoDB, Cloudinary, Vercel]

The full range web site of volunteer organization with events calendar, photo gallery, news pages etc. The project is under construction and includes work includes development, deployment and maintenance of the site, as well as creating and improving the content.

Multicook Brandon Landing Page

[React, Tailwind, Vercel]

Frontend project with SEO optimization, Google Workspace setup and business placing on Google Maps. Online business consultation and support for purchasing a domain name and hosting are provided.

Management system for web-shop managers & customer support [React, TypeScript, MUI, GraphQI, Prizma]

The system provides the possibility to manage customer's orders, create special offers, send invoices, get statistics, etc. The system is placed on top of the web-shop (Sparelys.no) in order to use the web store catalog while creating special offers on the fly.

Responsibilities: Updating the system: adding filters, user settings persisting, personalization and authorization, product customisation, updating visual design and creating responsive design.

Admin panel (dashboard) for web-shop data management [NextJs, TypeScript, Tailwind, GraphQl, Prizma]

The system provides the possibility to overview special offers, manage customer's data, create and update new users (online managers) of the web store. Also create and send links to customers, get statistics, etc. Responsibilities: Full-cycle creating a system from scratch

BackEnd and REST API for Recipes app [Node.js, Compass, MongoDB, Cloudinary, Swagger]

Pet-project. REST API, which provides operations for Recipes application. Authorization, search recipes by category, ingredient or title. Available to add own recipes, add to and remove from favorites, etc. DB based on MongoDB, file storage - Cloudinary, server - Express.

News Web Application [HTML5, SASS, JavaScript]

Team pet-project. The App is based on news API. Searching news by query, topic and date. Responsive design, light/dark mode. Used local storage for Favorite and Read pages. Embedded weather window. Role: Developer. Responsibility: header, dark/light mode, search form and fetching API

<u>Image Finder & Gallery</u>

[HTML5, SASS, JavaScript]

Pet-project. Website with request form, fetch API, image gallery and navigation through the gallery. Modal window, "load more" button.

View more projects